

PROFILE

In 20 years of writing software, I've covered a lot of ground. Drones and modern web, low-level networking code and distributed systems, dozens of languages, frameworks and operating systems. I am looking for a role where my skills and experience could bring maximum value to the table.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Physics — 1998 (Kyiv University) Languages: English, Ukrainian, Russian

CONTACT

PHONE: 778-837-6376

EMAIL:

vlad@orlenko.ca

Art & Logic — Senior Software Engineer 2010–2014

As a Senior Software Engineer at Art & Logic, I designed, implemented, and maintained complex software products. I handled all stages of project lifecycle, from requirement analysis and initial estimation to architecture design, implementation and support. Worked with teams of various sizes, 2-15 engineers. Filled the roles of Team Lead and Project Manager, as well as Engineer.

Notable Projects:

- Medical machine-learning application based on AngularJS, Django REST Framework, Compass/SASS, running on AWS.
- Inventory management system for Kroger, involving Pyramid, Fabric, jQuery, RESTful APIs and native iOS application.
- CRM system for Google, based on Google AppEngine, Django-nonrel, AngularJS, Compass/SASS, using Google+ API. Took PM and lead developer roles at various stages of the project, successfully handled challenges of intense dynamics within global Google marketing team.

Bjola Software — Software Contractor 2010–2014

VLAD ORLENKO

Software Engineer

WORK EXPERIENCE

${\bf Drone Deploy-Senior\,Software\,\,Engineer}$

2016-08-2020-05

As a Senior Software Engineer on the Flight team, I designed and implemented features for iOS and Android platforms, using TypeScript/Angular, Swift, Objective C, Java, and C++ on the frontend, and Python/Tornado, MongoDB, GraphQL on the backend.

As an engineer on the Computer Vision team, I took part in implementing real-time photogrammetry in the mobile app (C++).

As a backend engineer, I worked on the map-processing pipeline, web API, and integration with external services (API gateway). I worked with Docker, Kubernetes, Amazon and Google cloud services.

During engineering support rotations, I investigated and helped resolve real-world technical problems of the customers.

StyleSeat — Senior Software Engineer

2014-2016

As a Senior Full-stack Software Engineer, I implemented features such as client referral system (AngularJS/Cordova frontend, Django REST Framework on the backend, data-driven A/B testing approach to design decisions), parts of Elasticsearch setup, built Flask-based microservices and a marketing app with Django-CMS.

Besides large clients listed above, a number of projects for smaller companies and open-source initiatives are notable:

- Open-source public legal information system developed for British Columbia non-profits. PLEI, http://plei.publiclegaled.bc.ca, was developed using Django, Mezzanine CMS, and jQuery. Source code: https://github.com/orlenko/plei.
- Open-source web application for student initiatives and projects, created for SFU: http://sfpirg.ca. Django, Mezzanine, jQuery, Compass/SASS. Source code: https://github.com/orlenko/sfpirg.
- Open-source CMS for family-related non-profits in BC: FRP-BC, http://frpbc.ca. Uses Django, Fiber, jQuery. Source: https://aithub.com/orlenko/FRP.
- Implemented several hybrid hardware-software projects that involved a fusion of web technologies, mobile APIs, and custom low-level device interfaces. One such project was diVA (for 2C Visual Communications / Jigsaw Interactions), an interactive sensor-based presentation platform. Some photos of its application can be seen here: http://www.flickr.com/photos/2c-visualcommunications/. The product provided an extensible interactive framework with an API, enabling communications between distance sensors, cameras, temperature and humidity sensors, cell phones, Arduino-based devices, and high-precision video control software. The project was written in Python, using Twisted framework and ExtJS (now Sencha)-based UI for the web app portion of the project, proprietary C-based firmware for sensor devices, C-based apps for Arduino, and .NET compact framework for Windows phones.

Veriteq Instruments (acquired by Vaisala) — Software Developer 2005–2010

Developed the company's flagship product, viewLinc, a distributed software system for continuous temperature and humidity monitoring, alarming, and reports. During the time at Veriteq, turned viewLinc from a set of simple MFC-based applications into an extensible distributed web-based product written in Python/Twisted and JavaScript/ExtJS, with critical parts in C++, with an Oracle Berkeley DB back-end.

Apparent Networks (formerly jaalaM Technologies) — Software Developer 2002–2005

Designed and developed several subsystems of the AppareNet network diagnostics system. Created Sequencer, the AppareNet component that performs high-precision network measurements and observations. Sequencer is a portable ACE-based C++ software, available for Windows, Linux, Solaris and HP-UX. Developed a TAO-based CORBA layer for AppareNet Analysis Server. Was responsible for the choice of technologies for these components, as well as for design and implementation that would allow both code portability and optimization of critical code portions.

Pharox Automatisering B.V. — Software Developer

2001-2002

Developed inspection tools for European Chemical Industry Council (CEFIC), European Barge Inspection System (EBIS), and for Chemical Distribution Institute. As lead developer for this project, I designed and coded most of its server and client software, particularly, performed server-side database programming (PL/SQL stored procedures, database design, web interface—Oracle 9iAS, Oracle Portal), and created client application used by the inspectors (VB, VC++).

SoftIrbis Ltd — Software Developer

2000-2001

Developed database software using VB, VC++, SQL Server, Crystal Reports, for automating business processes (accounting/sales/warehousing). Wrote SQL scripts and VB code, developed custom ActiveX controls using VC++. The project was aimed at trading process automation for small-to-medium-size companies.

MacroChem JSC — Systems Administrator / Programmer

1999-2000

As an IT admin, took care of NT domain and an OpenBSD server that served as firewall and mail server. As a developer, worked on a marketing database project for the company, using VB and VC++.

REFERENCES: AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST